<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Bachelor of Arts (BA)</h3>
<p>The major is a flexible, interdisciplinary program offering opportunities for both wide, comparative study of South and Southeast Asian cultures, literature, religion, and history. The department teaches the following 13 languages: Bengali, Burmese, Filipino, Hindi, Indonesian, Khmer, Punjabi, Sanskrit, Tamil, Telugu, Thai, Urdu, and Vietnamese.</p>
<h3>Declaring the Major</h3>
<p>There are prerequisites to declaring the major: one semester of language work with a grade of B or higher AND one completed lower division/gateway course (<span class="sc_courseinline">S ASIAN 1A</span>, <span class="sc_courseinline">S ASIAN 1B</span>, <span class="sc_courseinline">SEASIAN 10A</span> or <span class="sc_courseinline">SEASIAN 10B</span>) with a grade of C or higher.</p>
<h3>Honors Program</h3>
<p>To be eligible for admission to the honors program, a student must attain a 3.5 grade- point average or higher in courses completed in the major, and a 3.3 grade-point average in all courses completed at the University. An honors thesis is required, as is registration in SSEASN H195 course based on student's area of study. Students who wish to participate must choose a thesis topic in consultation with their major adviser and apply for admission to the program through the departmental office no later than the first week of spring semester in their senior year.</p>
<h3>Minor Program</h3>
<p>Requirements:  One gateway course from, <span class="sc_courseinline">S ASIAN 1A</span>, <span class="structuredcontent" title="Inline Course - Double Click to Edit"><span><a class="bubblelink code" href="/2018-19/search/?P=S%20ASIAN%201B">S ASIAN 1B</a></span></span>, <span class="sc_courseinline">SEASIAN 10A</span> <em>or </em><span class="structuredcontent" title="Inline Course - Double Click to Edit"><span><a class="bubblelink code" href="/2018-19/search/?P=SEASIAN%2010B">SEASIAN 10B</a></span></span></p>
<p> <strong>AND</strong> five additional letter-graded upper-division courses (20 units) with 2.0 Min GPA</p>
<ul>
	<li>Only <strong>one</strong> course from outside the department will be accepted</li>
	<li>No more than <strong>two</strong> upper division language courses will be accepted</li>
</ul>
<p>For further information regarding how to declare the minor, please contact the department.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<majorrequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>In addition to the University, campus, and college requirements, listed on the College Requirements tab, students must fulfill the below requirements specific to their major program.</p>
<h3>General Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All courses taken to fulfill the major requirements below must be taken for graded credit, other than courses listed which are offered on a <em>Pass/No Pass</em> basis only. Other exceptions to this requirement are noted as applicable.</li>
	<li>No more than one upper division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student's major and minor programs, with the exception of minors offered outside of the College of Letters &amp; Science.</li>
	<li>A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 must be maintained in both upper and lower division courses used to fulfill the major requirements.</li>
</ol>
<p>For information regarding residency requirements and unit requirements, please see the College Requirements tab.</p>
<h3>Major Requirements: South and Southeast Asian Studies</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Four Semesters of Language Work</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Choose from: Bengali, Burmese, Filipino, Hindi, Indonesian, Khmer, Punjabi, Sanskrit, Tamil, Telugu, Thai, Urdu, and Vietnamese.</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Lower Division</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Choose two of the following courses:</span> <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">S ASIAN 1A</td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">S ASIAN 1B</td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">SEASIAN 10A</td><td>Introduction to the Civilization of Southeast Asia</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">SEASIAN 10B</td><td>Introduction to the Civilization of Southeast Asia</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Upper Division</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">At least 26 units for a letter grade that include intermediate/second-year level of any supported language and additional courses from 110 and above that include at least one course from &quot;Religion &amp; History&quot; and at least one course from &quot;Literature&quot;</span> <sup>2</sup></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<table border="0" width="100%" class="sc_footnotes"><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>1</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>It is possible to create a mixed South/Southeast Asian combination; please see an undergraduate faculty adviser to discuss this possibility.</p></td></tr></table>
]]>
</majorrequirementstext>
<minorrequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>Students who have a strong interest in an area of study outside their major often decide to complete a minor program. These programs have set requirements and are noted officially on the transcript in the memoranda section, but they are not noted on diplomas.</p>
<h3>General Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>All courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements below must be taken for graded credit.</li>
	<li>A minimum of three of the upper division courses taken to fulfill the minor requirements must be completed at UC Berkeley.</li>
	<li>A minimum grade point average (GPA) of 2.0 is required for courses used to fulfill the minor requirements.</li>
	<li>Courses used to fulfill the minor requirements may be applied toward the Seven-Course Breadth requirement, for Letters &amp; Science students.</li>
	<li>No more than one upper division course may be used to simultaneously fulfill requirements for a student's major and minor programs.</li>
	<li>All minor requirements must be completed prior to the last day of finals during the semester in which the student plans to graduate. Students who cannot finish all courses required for the minor by that time should see a College of Letters &amp; Science adviser.</li>
	<li>All minor requirements must be completed within the unit ceiling. (For further information regarding the unit ceiling, please see the College Requirements tab.)</li>
</ol>
<h3>Requirements</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Lower Division</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Choose one course from the following:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">S ASIAN 1A</td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">S ASIAN 1B</td><td>Course Not Available</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">SEASIAN 10A</td><td>Introduction to the Civilization of Southeast Asia</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">SEASIAN 10B</td><td>Introduction to the Civilization of Southeast Asia</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Upper Division</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select five upper division courses from the offerings of the department.</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<collegerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
 <p>Undergraduate students must fulfill the following requirements in addition to those required by their major program.</p> <p>For detailed lists of courses that fulfill college requirements, please review the <a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/">College of Letters &amp; Sciences</a> page in this Guide. For College advising appointments, please visit the <a href="https://ls.berkeley.edu/advising/about-undergraduate-advising-services">L&amp;S Advising</a> Pages. </p> <h3>University of California Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="http://writing.berkeley.edu/node/78"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-b6fc-99fe-5be6e0865dad">Entry Level Writing</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-c602-c395-1fb0f53c604b">All students who will enter the University of California as freshmen must demonstrate their command of the English language by fulfilling the Entry Level Writing requirement. Fulfillment of this requirement is also a prerequisite to enrollment in all reading and composition courses at UC Berkeley. </span></p> <h5><a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/american-history-institutions-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-ed90-bc30-8e7c7e9092f7">American History and American Institutions</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d403-fe3e-933e-7102e097ef4b">The American History and Institutions requirements are based on the principle that a US resident graduated from an American university, should have an understanding of the history and governmental institutions of the United States.</span></p> <h3><span>Berkeley Campus Requirement</span></h3> <h5><a href="http://americancultures.berkeley.edu/students/courses"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-3abc-dc51-fc563caacff1">American Cultures</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-47e1-1ad4-b918d33461cf">All undergraduate students at Cal need to take and pass this course in order to graduate. The requirement offers an exciting intellectual environment centered on the study of race, ethnicity and culture of the United States. AC courses offer students opportunities to be part of research-led, highly accomplished teaching environments, grappling with the complexity of American Culture.</span></p> <h3><span>College of Letters &amp; Science Essential Skills Requirements</span></h3> <h5><a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/quantitative-reasoning-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-a7b1-d295-ee03b476bcfe">Quantitative Reasoning</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-cbac-1c7a-d74abefae398">The Quantitative Reasoning requirement is designed to ensure that students graduate with basic understanding and competency in math, statistics, or computer science. The requirement may be satisfied by exam or by taking an approved course.</span></p> <h5><a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/foreign-language-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d404-ff23-6ff3-47abec092456">Foreign Language</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-12d9-db19-1b37f6639ef7">The Foreign Language requirement may be satisfied by demonstrating proficiency in reading comprehension, writing, and conversation in a foreign language equivalent to the second semester college level, either by passing an exam or by completing approved course work.</span></p> <h5><a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/reading-composition-requirement/"><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-3e15-2491-27223f91e87d">Reading and Composit</span>ion</a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-4ef4-4b87-0d26195a0d3c">In order to provide </span>a solid foundation in reading, writing, and critical thinking the College requires two semesters of lower division work in composition in sequence. Students must complete parts A &amp; B reading and composition courses by the end of their second semester and a second-level course by the end of their fourth semester.</p> <h3>College of Letters &amp; Science 7 Course Breadth Requirements</h3> <h5><a href="/2018-19/undergraduate/colleges-schools/letters-science/#breadthrequirementstext"><span id="docs-internal-guid-79a9fe70-d405-7c7e-e34f-837b91cc1d58">Breadth Requirements</span></a></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d405-9db4-c30e-bca05ecf44f3">The undergraduate breadth requirements provide Berkeley students with a rich and varied educational experience outside of their major program. As the foundation of a liberal arts education, breadth courses give students a view into the intellectual life of the University while introducing them to a multitude of perspectives and approaches to research and scholarship. Engaging students in new disciplines and with peers from other majors, the breadth experience strengthens interdisciplinary connections and context that prepares Berkeley graduates to understand and solve the complex issues of their day.</span></p> <h3><span id="docs-internal-guid-abca8c8f-d405-c4ad-0be7-1638c654345c">Unit Requirements</span></h3> <ul> 	<li> 	<p>120 total units</p> 	</li> 	<li> 	<p>Of the 120 units, 36 must be upper division units</p> 	</li> 	<li>Of the 36 upper division units, 6 must be taken in courses offered outside your major department</li> </ul> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-2bb674c5-d406-43a4-39ed-40d6e86d6760">Residence Requirements</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-8d38-492a-067b2e0bac2d">For units to be considered in &quot;residence,&quot; you must be registered in courses on the Berkeley campus as a student in the College of Letters &amp; Science. Most students automatically fulfill the residence requirement by attending classes here for four years. In general, there is no need to be concerned about this requirement, unless you go abroad for a semester or year or want to take courses at another institution or through UC Extension during your senior year. In these cases, you should make an appointment to meet an adviser to determine how you can meet the Senior Residence Requirement.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-a2e5-35d5-82895d287218">Note: Courses taken through UC Extension do not count toward residence.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-44b2bced-d406-cb13-a0f5-0c6f75ed8972">Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-e3bd-f620-e9bef1331f97">After you become a senior (with 90 semester units earned toward your BA degree), you must complete at least 24 of the remaining 30 units in residence in at least two semesters. To count as residence, a semester must consist of at least 6 passed units. Intercampus Visitor, EAP, and UC Berkeley-Washington Program (UCDC) units are excluded.</span></p> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d406-f7f7-c9da-c2732368bc4e">You may use a Berkeley Summer Session to satisfy one semester of the Senior Residence requirement, provided that you successfully complete 6 units of course work in the Summer Session and that you have been enrolled previously in the college.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-abb18f5b-d407-0e0f-9d41-83c0ea3c3c7b">Modified Senior Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-3956-aeef-b67b71969fca">Participants in the UC Education Abroad Program (EAP), Berkeley Summer Abroad, or the UC Berkeley Washington Program (UCDC) may meet a Modified Senior Residence requirement by completing 24 (excluding EAP) of their final 60 semester units in residence. At least 12 of these 24 units must be completed after you have completed 90 units.</span></p> <h5><span id="docs-internal-guid-62f287bf-d407-4ca6-5bbd-2d1393418d66">Upper Division Residence Requirement</span></h5> <p><span id="docs-internal-guid-82322469-d407-6060-9575-98782777275a">You must complete in residence a minimum of 18 units of upper division courses (excluding UCEAP units), 12 of which must satisfy the requirements for your major.</span></p>
]]>
</collegerequirementstext>
<studentlearninggoalstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Mission</h3>
<p>The mission of the Department of South and Southeast Asian Studies is to enable students to learn about the cultures and civilizations of South and Southeast Asia. The department teaches 13 languages and is an indispensable resource for programs in many other departments and areas.</p>
<p>For undergraduate majors, the department stresses an interdisciplinary approach and expects students to specialize in one of three areas—literature, religion, or cultural history. To this end, there are two tracks for majors—one that emphasizes the study of civilization and does not require language and one that requires the students to do four semesters of language work in addition to more general studies. UC Berkeley has an extraordinary number of experts in many areas of South and Southeast Asian Studies, and students are encouraged to take advantage of relevant courses in departments such as history, music, political science, ethnic studies, art history, linguistics, gender and women’s studies, and English. Qualified undergraduates are also encouraged to participate in graduate seminars.</p>
<h3>Learning Goals for the Major</h3>
<p>There are two tracks in the South and Southeast Asian Studies major—one that emphasizes the study of civilization and does not require language, and one that requires the students to do four semesters of language work in addition to more general studies. Within each track, students specialize in an area (South or Southeast Asia).</p>
<h4>Goals for the Language Track</h4>
<ol>
	<li>Students should have mastered the grammar (included complex grammatical features) of at least one South and Southeast Asian language (Sanskrit, Hindi, Tamil, Urdu, Punjabi, Bengali, Telugu for South Asia and Indonesian, Thai, Tagalog, Vietnamese, Khmer for Southeast). They should be able to read stories, newspapers, and the like in the modern language in which they specialize.</li>
	<li>They should be able to speak and get about using the language (if relevant) and to write simple prose in the modern language.</li>
	<li>For classic languages such as Sanskrit, students should have the basic facility in reading a variety of different genres in the original, and they should be comfortable using standard resource materials such as dictionaries, traditional grammars, and online resources. They are also expected to be able to engage critically with the pertinent secondary sources relevant to the texts being read.</li>
	<li>They should have a sound knowledge of one culture or area of South or Southeast Asia.</li>
	<li>They should have a broad general acquaintance with either South or Southeast Asia including a good knowledge of cultural history, literature, and/or religion.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Goals for the Civilization Track</h4>
<ol>
	<li>Students should have a thorough understanding of the histories and culture of either South or Southeast Asia.</li>
	<li>In lieu of acquiring detailed knowledge of one of the cultural/linguistic areas of South or Southeast Asia, they are expected to deepen their mastery of cultural history or religion of South or Southeast Asia.</li>
	<li>They should specialize in a particular national tradition and/or in a particular approach to the region (historical, literary, art, performative).</li>
</ol>
]]>
</studentlearninggoalstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Languages and Culture:</h3>
<div class="clearfix">
<div class="cola">
<ul>
	<li><a href="#South and Southeast Asian Studies">South and Southeast Asian Studies</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="colb">
<ul>
	<li><a href="#South Asian">South Asian</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h3>Languages:</h3>
<div class="clearfix">
<div class="cola">
<ul>
	<li><a href="#Bengali">Bengali</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Filipino">Filipino</a></li>
	<li><a href="#HindiUrdu">Hindi-Urdu</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Indonesian">Indonesian</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Khmer">Khmer</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Punjabi">Punjabi</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="colb">
<ul>
	<li><a href="#Sanskrit">Sanskrit</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Tamil">Tamil</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Telugu">Telugu</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Thai">Thai</a></li>
	<li><a href="#Vietnamese">Vietnamese</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="South and Southeast Asian Studies" name="South and Southeast Asian Studies"></a>South and Southeast Asian Studies</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN C220</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Buddhism and Buddhist Texts</span> <span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Content varies with student interests. The course will normally focus on classical Buddhist texts that exist in multiple recensions and languages, including Chinese, Sanskrit, and Tibetan.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Buddhism and Buddhist Texts:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="844">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BUDDSTD C220/EA LANG C220</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Buddhism and Buddhist Texts:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290A</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: South Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Spring 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: South Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="223">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2.5-12.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: South Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290B</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: Tamil</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2016 8 Week Session, Summer 2015 8 Week Session, Fall 2014<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="972">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290C</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: Hindi-Urdu</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2016 8 Week Session, Summer 2015 8 Week Session, Fall 2014<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: Hindi-Urdu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="717">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong><br/>
6 weeks - 2.5-12.5 hours of independent study per week<br/>
8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: Hindi-Urdu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290D</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: Malay/Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2016 8 Week Session, Summer 2015 8 Week Session, Fall 2014<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: Malay/Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="528">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: Malay/Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290E</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: Southeast Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: Southeast Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="947">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: Southeast Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 290F</span> <span class="title">Special Studies: Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">1 - 5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2016 8 Week Session, Summer 2015 8 Week Session, Spring 2015<br/>
Students may enroll in more than one section of 290, but the total number of units of Special Study in any one semester may not exceed 12.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Special Studies: Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="662">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-5 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-9 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Special Studies: Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299A</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: South Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Fall 2016, Summer 2016 8 Week Session<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: South Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="785">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: South Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299B</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Tamil</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Fall 2014<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="452">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299C</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Hindi-Urdu</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Hindi-Urdu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="61">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Hindi-Urdu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299D</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Malay-Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2018, Fall 2017<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Malay-Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="715">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Malay-Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299E</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Southeast Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Southeast Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="830">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Southeast Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 299F</span> <span class="title">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">1 - 12 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2014, Spring 2014<br/>
Normally reserved for students directly engaged in writing the doctoral dissertation.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="608">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Advanced candidate with consent of thesis supervisor and graduate adviser</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 2-22.5 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Dissertation Preparation and Related Research: Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 601A</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Masters Students: South Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Spring 2016, Fall 2014<br/>
Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: South Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="613">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for Master's degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong><br/>
6 weeks - 1-8 hours of independent study per week<br/>
8 weeks - 1-8 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: South Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 601C</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Masters Students: Hindi-Urdu</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Hindi-Urdu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="317">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for Master's degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Hindi-Urdu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 601D</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Masters Students: Malay-Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Malay-Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="999">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for Master's degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Malay-Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 601E</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Masters Students: Southeast Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Southeast Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="861">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for Master's degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Southeast Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 601F</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Masters Students: Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study for the comprehensive or language requirements in consultation with the graduate adviser.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="660">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for Master's degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Masters Students: Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602A</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: South Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: South Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="796">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: South Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602B</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Tamil</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="740">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602C</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Hindi-Urdu</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Hindi-Urdu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="219">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Hindi-Urdu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602D</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Malay-Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2014, Spring 2014, Fall 2013<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Malay-Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="927">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Malay-Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602E</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Southeast Asian Studies</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2014, Spring 2014<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Southeast Asian Studies:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="342">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Southeast Asian Studies:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S,SEASN 602F</span> <span class="title">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Spring 2017, Fall 2016, Fall 2014<br/>
Individual study in consultation with the major field adviser, intended to provide an opportunity for qualified students to prepare themselves for the various examinations required for candidates for the Ph.D.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="528">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> For candidates for doctoral degree</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 0 hours of independent study per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South and Southeast Asian Studies/Graduate examination preparation</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Individual Study for Doctoral Students: Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="South Asian" name="South Asian"></a>South Asian</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S ASIAN C214</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Tibetan Buddhism</span> <span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2012<br/>
This course provides a place for graduate-level seminars in Tibetan Buddhism that rely primarily on secondary sources and Tibetan texts in translation. Content will vary between semesters but will typically focus on a particular theme. Themes will be chosen according to student interests, with an eye toward introducing students to the breadth of available western scholarship on Tibet, from classics in the field to the latest publications.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Tibetan Buddhism:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="388">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South Asian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Dalton</p>
<p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BUDDSTD C214/TIBETAN C214</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Tibetan Buddhism:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S ASIAN 215A</span> <span class="title">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts</span> <span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2009, Fall 2008, Fall 2007<br/>
This graduate seminar focuses on reading a wide spectrum of Indian Buddhist texts in the Sanskrit (or Pali) original introducing the students to different genres, and different aspects of Indian Buddhism. The students taking the course for 2 units (rather than 4) will be expected to prepare thoroughly every week for the reading of Buddhist texts in the original. They will also be expected to read all related secondary literature that is assigned to supplement the study of the primary source material. In contrast to the students taking the course for 4 units, they will not be expected to write a term paper or to prepare special presentations for class.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="928">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 215A is prerequisite to 215B. One year of Sanskrit and/or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South Asian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S ASIAN C215</span> <span class="title">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts</span> <span class="hours">2 - 4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2018, Fall 2017<br/>
This graduate seminar focuses on reading a wide spectrum of Indian Buddhist texts in the Sanskrit (or Pali) original introducing the students to different genres, and different aspects of Indian Buddhism. The students taking the course for two units (rather than four) will be expected to prepare thoroughly every week for the reading of Buddhist texts in the original. They will also be expected to read all related secondary literature that is assigned to supplement the study of the primary source material. In contrast to the students taking the course for four units, they will not be expected to write a term paper or to prepare special presentations for class.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="912">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students will receive no credit for South Asian C215/ Group in Buddhist Studies C215 after completing South Asian 215A, or South Asian C215A/Group in Buddhist Studies C215A.&lt;BR/&gt;</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South Asian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Rospatt</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> South Asian C215A/Group in Buddhist Studies C215A</p>
<p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BUDDSTD C215</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Indian Buddhist Texts:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">S ASIAN C224</span> <span class="title">Readings in Tibetan Buddhist Texts</span> <span class="hours">2 or 4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Fall 2017, Spring 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This seminar provides an introduction to a broad range of Tibetan Buddhist texts, including chronicles and histories, biographical literature, doctrinal treatises, canonical texts, ritual manuals, pilgrimage guides, and liturgical texts. It is intended for graduate students interested in premodern Tibet from any perspective. Students are required to do all of the readings in the original classical Tibetan. It will also serve as a tools and methods for the study of Tibetan Buddhist literature, including standard lexical and bibliographic references, digital resources, and secondary literature in modern languages. The content of the course will vary from semester to semester to account for the needs and interests of particular students.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Tibetan Buddhist Texts:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="598">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3-3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> South Asian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Dalton</p>
<p><strong>Also listed as:</strong> BUDDSTD C224/TIBETAN C224</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Tibetan Buddhist Texts:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Bengali" name="Bengali"></a>Bengali</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">BANGLA 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Bengali</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2015, Fall 2013<br/>
Students will be expected to acquire knowledge of the basic grammar of Bengali, such that they learn to read simple graded texts and to speak at the &quot;low intermediate&quot; level by the end of the year.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Bengali:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="956">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A is prerequisite to 1B, or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture and 2.5 hours of reading per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Bengali/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Bengali:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">BANGLA 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Bengali</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2016, Spring 2014<br/>
Students will be expected to acquire knowledge of the basic grammar of Bengali, such that they learn to read simple graded texts and to speak at the &quot;low intermediate&quot; level by the end of the year.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Bengali:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="141">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A is prerequisite to 1B, or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Bengali/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Bengali:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">BANGLA 101A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Bengali</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2018, Fall 2016<br/>
Students are expected to be able to read, with the aid of a dictionary, modern Bengali literature, and speak at a &quot;high-intermediate&quot; level by the end of the year. There will be viewing of Bengali videos at a mutually agreed upon time and in class from time to time.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Bengali:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="219">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1B is prerequisite to 101A; 101A is prerequisite to 101B; or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of session per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 10 weeks - 7.5 hours of session per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Bengali/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Bengali:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">BANGLA 101B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Bengali</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2017, Spring 2015, Spring 2013<br/>
Students are expected to be able to read, with the aid of a dictionary, modern Bengali literature, and speak at a &quot;high-intermediate&quot; level by the end of the year. There will be viewing of Bengali videos at a mutually agreed upon time and in class from time to time.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Bengali:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="1">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101A or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of session per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 10 weeks - 7.5 hours of session per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Bengali/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Bengali:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Filipino" name="Filipino"></a>Filipino</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Filipino</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
A systematic introduction to the grammar, sentence patterns, and essential vocabulary of modern standard Filipino. Emphasis is placed on extensive practice in idiomatic Filipino conversation, with additional practice in reading and writing Filipino.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="158">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A: None. 1B: 1A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Tagalog 1A</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Filipino</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
A systematic introduction to the grammar, sentence patterns, and essential vocabulary of modern standard Filipino. Emphasis is placed on extensive practice in idiomatic Filipino conversation, with additional practice in reading and writing Filipino.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="250">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Gosalvez</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Tagalog 1B</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W1X</span> <span class="title">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This course is an elementary Filipino class designed for heritage learners, and the first course in a sequence (Filipino W1X and W1Y). Using the functional-situational approach, the course builds on students’ passive vocabulary to harness four skills: listening, speaking, reading, and writing. Students develop skills enabling them to: talk/write about the self, family, and community; talk/write about activities and interactions such as going to the doctor or shopping; read simple texts; and write short paragraphs. Combines real-time meetings using Adobe Connect and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="626">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of web-based lecture and 1 hour of web-based discussion per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of web-based lecture and 2.5 hours of web-based discussion per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W1Y</span> <span class="title">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
This course is an elementary Filipino class designed for heritage learners, and the second course in a sequence (Filipino W1X and W1Y). Using the functional-situational approach, the course builds on students’ passive vocabulary to harness four skills: listening, speaking, reading, and writing. Students develop skills enabling them to: talk/write about the self, family, and community; talk/write about activities and interactions such as going to the doctor or shopping; read simple texts; and write short paragraphs. Combines real-time meetings using Adobe Connect and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="590">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 1A or W1X</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of web-based lecture and 1 hour of web-based discussion per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of web-based lecture and 2.5 hours of web-based discussion per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 15</span> <span class="title">Intensive Introductory Filipino</span> <span class="hours">10 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Summer 2012 8 Week Session<br/>
Provides the learner with essential vocabulary and study of sentence structures and grammar. Topics include: everyday life, the use of language in negotiations in the community, language and culture; and the history of Tagalog/Pilipino/Filipino. Students read simple texts and write short essays/creative pieces.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intensive Introductory Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="31">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 20 hours of lecture and 5 hours of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Aban</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intensive Introductory Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W15X</span> <span class="title">Intensive Intro Filipino for Heritage Learners Online</span> <span class="hours">10 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Summer 2018 10 Week Session<br/>
This course is an intensive elementary class designed for heritage learners. Using the functional-situational approach, the course builds on students’ passive vocabulary to harness four skills: listening, speaking, reading, and writing. Students develop skills enabling them to: talk/write about the self, family, and community; talk/write about activities and interactions such as going to the doctor or shopping; read simple texts; and write short paragraphs. Combines real-time meetings using Adobe Connect and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intensive Intro Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="537">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 10 weeks - 15 hours of web-based lecture and 5 hours of web-based discussion per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intensive Intro Filipino for Heritage Learners Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Filipino</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
The goal of this course is to enable students to increase their proficiency in Filipino to at least the intermediate-high level of the national ACTFL Proficiency Guidelines. While speaking and listening comprehension will be stressed, training in reading and writing Filipino will be an integral part of instruction. Films and video/audio materials will supplement written texts.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="786">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A-1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 100AB</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Filipino AB</span> <span class="hours">9 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Summer 2018 8 Week Session<br/>
This is an intermediate class with emphasis on four basic skills: listening, speaking, reading, and writing. The first part of the course involves a review and expansion of vocabulary and grammar learned in Introductory Filipino through dialogues, listening, reading and writing exercises. Then, students learn four necessary skills in the effective use of Filipino: describing a person, place, or feelings; narrating a story or an incident; defining and explaining; and reasoning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Filipino AB:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="281">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 1AB or Filipino 15 or Filipino XY or Placement Exam or Consent of Instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 10 hours of lecture and 7 hours of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam not required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Filipino AB:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Filipino</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Summer 2016 Second 6 Week Session<br/>
The goal of this course is to enable students to increase their proficiency in Filipino to at least the intermediate-high level of the national ACTFL Proficiency Guidelines. While speaking and listening comprehension will be stressed, training in reading and writing Filipino will be an integral part of instruction. Films and video/audio materials will supplement written texts.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="944">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A-1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Filipino Online</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
First half of the intermediate class series with emphasis on four skills in the effective use of Filipino: describing people, places, and feelings; narrating a story or incident; defining and explaining; and reasoning. Vocabulary is expanded through dialogues and authentic texts. At the end of the class, students should have a firm grasp of grammatical structures, write short texts, and converse with fluency. Combines real-time meetings using Adobe Connect and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Filipino Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="939">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 1A and 1B or Filipino W1X and W1Y or equivalent or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Filipino Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Filipino Online</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Second half of the intermediate class series with emphasis on four skills in the effective use of Filipino: describing people, places, and feelings; narrating a story or incident; defining and explaining; and reasoning. Vocabulary is expanded through dialogues and authentic texts. At the end of the class, students should have a firm grasp of grammatical structures, write short texts, and converse with fluency. Combines real-time meetings using Adobe Connect and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Filipino Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="854">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 100A or Filipino W100A or equivalent or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 12.5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Filipino Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 101A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Filipino</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2015<br/>
Students read and discuss essays on language, literature, and Phillippine society, and literary texts. Topics include language and the nation; poetry and discourse; language and ideology; and &quot;pananalinghaga&quot; (tropes/metaphors) in understanding society. The students choose whether they would like to go on a creative (poetry, fiction) or a research track (essay).</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="230">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A-100B or equivalent, or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN 101B</span> <span class="title">Advanced Filipino</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2016, Spring 2015<br/>
Students read and discuss essays on language, literature, and Phillippine society, and literary texts. Topics include language and the nation; poetry and discourse; language and ideology; and &quot;pananalinghaga&quot; (tropes/metaphors) in understanding society. The students choose whether they would like to go on a creative (poetry, fiction) or a research track (essay).</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Filipino:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="678">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A-100B, or equivalent, or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Filipino:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W101A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Filipino Online</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2015<br/>
First half of the advanced class series. This online class focuses on: reading skills for texts (articles, opinion columns, literary texts, and academic essays) with abstract vocabulary, idiomatic expressions, and complex sentences; listening skills for authentic texts; and writing skills in exposition and argumentation. We will work with examples of the Filipino language through texts written in 19th-century Tagalog, Commonwealth-era Pilipino, and contemporary Filipino.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Filipino Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="833">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 100A-100B, Filipino W100A-W100B, or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Filipino Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W101B</span> <span class="title">Advanced Filipino Online</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2017<br/>
Second half of the advanced class series. The class focuses on: reading skills for texts (articles, opinion columns, literary texts, and academic essays) with abstract vocabulary, idiomatic expressions, and complex sentences; listening skills for authentic texts; and writing skills in exposition and argumentation. We will work with examples of the Filipino language through texts written in 19th-century Tagalog, Commonwealth-era Pilipino, and contemporary Filipino.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Filipino Online:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="545">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino 101A or W101A, or equivalent, or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 7.5 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios-Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Filipino Online:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W120A</span> <span class="title">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
This is a language class designed for students planning to be in the medical professions. In the first course of this two-semester sequence (A/B), students learn basic speaking, listening, reading and writing skills. Using a functional approach, the class focuses on conversational skills in the clinic/hospital setting; vocabulary on the body, illnesses, and medical histories; and giving simple instructions and explanations. Combines real-time meetings (Adobe Connect) and online learning.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="566">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 10 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">FILIPN W120B</span> <span class="title">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Prior to 2007<br/>
Filipino 120B is the second course of a two-semester course sequence. Students develop language skills so that they can discuss: focus systems (i.e., ears, eyes, nose, throat; heart and blood pressure; infectious diseases) and special care (children, elderly, preventive health). Designed for those who have taken 120A or with basic knowledge of Filipino, the course seeks to develop the ability to: describe illnesses in detail; provide explanations and instructions; and interpret and translate.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="873">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Filipino W120A or completion of placement exam</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 6 weeks - 10 hours of web-based lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Online:</strong> This is an online course.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Filipino/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Barrios Leblanc</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Filipino for Special Purposes: Medical Professions:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="HindiUrdu" name="HindiUrdu"></a>Hindi-Urdu</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">HIN-URD 104A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Urdu</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2015<br/>
Reading of Urdu prose and poetry in a variety of literary and scholarly styles; composition. Topics in advanced grammar; designed to improve proficiency in speaking, listening, reading, and writing. Students will be expected to converse in a clearly participatory fashion, initiate, sustain, and bring to closure a wide variety of communicative tasks using diverse language strategies.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Urdu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="919">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two years of Urdu or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Hindi-Urdu/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Urdu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Khmer" name="Khmer"></a>Khmer</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Khmer</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Provides a command of the basic structures of standard spoken Cambodian and tools for reading and writing elementary texts. Through use of computer-based materials, a textbook, and communicative practice, students gain a foundation in &quot;survival&quot; spoken Khmer. This involves memorization of question and answer exchanges in Khmer which students are likely to encounter in modern Cambodia. Topics include greetings, speaking to teachers and elders and discussing language learning, talking about family and personal history, and food. Students learn the Khmer alphabet and important sight-words and to read and write simple sentences on everyday topics. Intended for non-native speakers of Khmer with no oral or aural comprehension in the language. Students will also learn important basic behaviors and courtesies necessary for smooth interaction in Khmer society and culture.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="403">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Khmer</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Students complete their study of everyday standard Khmer to a &quot;survival&quot; level. While the memorization of vocabulary and common personal exchanges practiced in 1A will make up the majority of material studied, students will have some opportunity to learn to improvise and talk about personal work and research interests in Khmer. Topics include transportation and directions, the world of work, religion, health, and conducting daily life in Cambodia. Students learn to read simple authentic texts such as folk tales, personal letters, forms, and roadside signs. Students continue their study of culturally appropriate behavior in the context of Khmer culture, including notions of &quot;saving face&quot; and maintaining social harmony, and how these are expressed in both spoken language and in one's actions.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="298">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A or equivalent</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Khmer</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Non-native speakers who have completed Beginning Khmer will build spoken proficiency with emphasis on everyday &quot;storytelling&quot; and the expression of emotions, feelings, and opinions. Students will gain experience reading progressively difficult authentic Khmer texts, including folk tales and newspaper articles. Native speakers with family exposure to Khmer will be introduced to the writing system. They will quickly &quot;catch up&quot; with non-native classmates who have studied the writing system before. All students will study important patterns and structures in Khmer grammar and morphology, and gain a foundation in formal spoken Khmer, express opinions and positions, form arguments, and learn to discuss a variety of topics with educated Khmer speakers. These include Khmer religion, village culture, news, and advertising.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="762">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A-1B or equivalent, or home exposure to Khmer</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Khmer</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Students learn to read roadside signs, scholarly articles, and an entire Khmer novel. Topics include current events in Cambodia, Cambodian history and politics, and a basic overview of traditional Khmer literature. Much of this study will be accomplished by working on projects in groups with other students. One such project will involve the preparation and performance of a play based on sections of the modern Khmer novel students read in this course. All students will design and carry out an independent research project on the topic of their choice (which will account for 30% of the final grade), and present their research at the end of the second semester to an audience of their peers, entirely in Khmer.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="418">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 101A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Khmer</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This course continues the themes and goals of 100B. Students will focus on the same broad topics covered in Intermediate Khmer--religion, traditional culture, and the language of public information (news and advertising)--but they will learn more advanced vocabulary and grammatical structures necessary for the discussion of these topics with educated native speakers, and read more advanced texts dealing with these topics than the Intermediate students. Additional material beyond the Intermediate curriculum includes reading and analyzing historical folk tales, learning to discuss the rice-farming cycle, and acquiring the tools to discuss research and &quot;development&quot; work in Cambodia at a sophisticated level.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="364">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two years of Khmer or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">KHMER 101B</span> <span class="title">Advanced Khmer</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Students will read advanced texts dealing with the topics of politics and history. They will also gain exposure to traditional verse texts, and read, discuss, and undertake group projects based on a variety of modern Khmer short stories. As in the case with Intermediate Khmer, students will also undertake substantial independent study, culminating in a final oral presentation. However, the standard by which both written and oral material will be judged will be much higher for Advanced students. Special attention will be paid to formal speaking style and advanced grammatical structures in Khmer for all students, and colloquial spoken expression for non-native speakers.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Khmer:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="784">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two years of Khmer or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Khmer/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Smith, F.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Khmer:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Indonesian" name="Indonesian"></a>Indonesian</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Survey of grammar, graded exercises, and readings drawn from Indonesian texts, leading to a mastery of basic language patterns, essential vocabulary, and to achievement of basic reading, writing, and conversational competence. Emphasis on developing communicative skills.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="676">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students who have passed MALAY/I 1A will not get credit for INDONES 1A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Lunde</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 1A</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Survey of grammar, graded exercises, and readings drawn from Indonesian texts, leading to a mastery of basic language patterns, essential vocabulary, and to achievement of basic reading, writing, and conversational competence. Emphasis on developing communicative skills.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="431">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Completion of <a class="bubblelink code" href="/2018-19/search/?P=INDONES%201A">INDONES 1A</a> (formerly MALAYI 1A) or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students who have passed MALAY/I 1B do not get credit for INDONES 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Lunde</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 1B</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Readings in Indonesian texts, including newspapers, journals, and literature exploring a variety of styles. Systematic study of grammatical and lexical problems arising from these readings. Advanced exercises in composition, oral and written communicative skills, and cultural competence.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="860">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A-1B</p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students who have passed MALAY/I 100A do not get credit for INDONES 100A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Lunde</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 100A</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Indonesian</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Readings in Indonesian texts, including newspapers, journals, and literature exploring a variety of styles. Systematic study of grammatical and lexical problems arising from these readings. Advanced exercises in composition, oral and written communicative skills, and cultural competence.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Indonesian:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="798">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Successful completion of <a class="bubblelink code" href="/2018-19/search/?P=INDONES%201B">INDONES 1B</a> (formerly MALAY/I 1B) or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students who have passed MALAY/I 100B do not get credit for INDONES 100B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 100B</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Indonesian:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 210A</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Various aspects of Indonesian and Malay language, history and development of the language, classical literature, drama, oral literature, modern literature of Indonesia and Malaysia, and dialect studies. Applies various theoretical approaches to the study of the language and literature.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="395">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Tiwon</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 210A</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 210B</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
Various aspects of Malay language and literature, history and development of the language, classical literature, drama, oral literature, modern literature of Indonesia and Malaysia, and dialect studies. Applies various theoretical approaches to the study of the language and literature.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="109">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Tiwon</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 210B</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Malay Letters and Oral Traditions:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">INDONES 232</span> <span class="title">Readings in Modern Indonesian and Malaysian Literature</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Not yet offered<br/>
This course will focus on the 20th century literatures of Indonesia and Malaysia. Emphasis will be on the socio-cultural matrix of such modern genres as the novel, the short story, and poetry. Lectures and most course work in Indonesian.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Modern Indonesian and Malaysian Literature:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="787">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two years of Malay/Indonesian or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Credit Restrictions:</strong> Students who have taken MAYALY/I 132 or MALAY/I 232 will not receive credit for INDONES 232</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Indonesian/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Formerly known as:</strong> Malay/Indonesian 232</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Modern Indonesian and Malaysian Literature:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Punjabi" name="Punjabi"></a>Punjabi</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">PUNJABI 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Punjabi</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Gurmukhi script. Survey of grammar. Graded exercises, leading to a mastery of basic language patterns, essential vocabulary, and achievement of basic reading and writing skills.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Punjabi:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="677">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A is prerequisite to 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Punjabi/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Ubhi, Upkar</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Punjabi:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">PUNJABI 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Punjabi</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Gurmukhi script. Survey of grammar. Graded exercises, leading to a mastery of basic language patterns, essential vocabulary, and achievement of basic reading and writing skills.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Punjabi:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="780">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Punjabi/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Ubhi</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Punjabi:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">PUNJABI 15</span> <span class="title">Intensive Elementary Punjabi</span> <span class="hours">10 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Summer 2000 10 Week Session, Summer 1998 10 Week Session, Summer 1997 10 Week Session<br/>
A comprehensive introduction to modern standard Punjabi as spoken in India and Pakistan. The Gurmukhi writing system; pronunciation; asquisition of grammar and basic vocabulary through graded exercises and readings; special emphasis on the ability to speak and understand Punjabi.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intensive Elementary Punjabi:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="253">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 20 hours of lecture and 5 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Punjabi/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Singh</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intensive Elementary Punjabi:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">PUNJABI 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Punjabi</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Focus on reading, writing and speaking Punjabi more fluently in formal and informal contexts. Selected readings vary every semester. These form the starting point to stimulate students' own writings which include a long interview with a Punjabi elder from the wider community. These may be recorded in the students' own voices and form a contribution to the ongoing &quot;Punjabi Voices&quot; project. Review of grammar provided as needed in addition to the introduction of more complex grammatical structures. Grading based on performance in class and final presentation, weekly quizzes, two midterms, and a final.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Punjabi:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="105">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1B is prerequisite to 100A; 100A is prerequisite to 100B</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Punjabi/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructors:</strong> Ubhi, Upkar</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Punjabi:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">PUNJABI 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Punjabi</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Focus on reading, writing and speaking Punjabi more fluently in formal and informal contexts. Selected readings vary every semester. These form the starting point to stimulate students' own writings which include a long interview with a Punjabi elder from the wider community. These may be recorded in the students' own voices and form a contribution to the ongoing &quot;Punjabi Voices&quot; project. Review of grammar provided as needed in addition to the introduction of more complex grammatical structures. Grading based on performance in class and final presentation, weekly quizzes, two midterms, and a final.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Punjabi:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="545">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Punjabi/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Ubhi</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Punjabi:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Sanskrit" name="Sanskrit"></a>Sanskrit</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 100A</span> <span class="title">Elementary Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Elements of Sanskrit grammar and practice in reading Sanskrit texts.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Elementary Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="222">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> S. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Elementary Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 100B</span> <span class="title">Elementary Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Elements of Sanskrit grammar and practice in reading Sanskrit texts.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Elementary Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="844">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Completion of <a class="bubblelink code" href="/2018-19/search/?P=SANSKR%20100A">SANSKR 100A</a> or equivalent</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> S. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Elementary Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 101A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Sanskrit: Epic and Puracic Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Fall 2016, Spring 2015<br/>
Introduces students to the itihasa/puraic traditions and related commentarial style of Sanskrit. An extended passage from Valmiki's Ramayaada, Vyasa's Mahabharata, or one of the Mahapuradas is normally read with commentary, if available. The development of strong reading skills is the focus of the class. Additionally, students are introduced to the use of hard copy and web-based resources. Grammar is reviewed and explained as needed. Students are also introduced to the current scholarship on epic literature. Students are expected to memorize at least one verse per class for recitation. Emphasis is placed on correct prosody and pronunciation. Submission of an annotated translation project, assigned in class, is required.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Epic and Puracic Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="496">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p>
<p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Course content changes every semester and may be repeated for credit. Reading of texts in the original language. Students are expected to prepare readings for translation in class. Mastering of grammar and genre-specific style is emphasized. Additionally students skills in writing, listening, and speaking of Sanskrit are further developed.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100B. 101B may be taken before 101A with consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4.5 hours of lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong><br/>
6 weeks - 8 hours of lecture per week<br/>
8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> S. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Epic and Puracic Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 101B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sastraic (Scientific) Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Spring 2017, Fall 2015<br/>
Introduces students to Sanskrit sastra and related commentary. Reading selections are generally taken from either the grammatical (vyakaraada), literary critical )alakarasatra) or the philosophical (darsana) tradition, including such works as Mahabhaya, Tarkasagraha, Kavyadarsa, etc. Reading skills and familiarity with resources - hard copy and web-based - as well as current trends and scholarship in the relevant areas are emphasized. Grammar is reviewed and explained as needed. Students are expected to memorize at least one verse per class. Emphasis is placed on correct prosody and pronunciation. Submission of an annotated translation or similar project, assigned in class, is required.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sastraic (Scientific) Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="261">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p>
<p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Course content changes every semester and may be repeated for credit. Intensive language instruction - reading of texts in the original language. Students are expected to prepare readings for translation in class. Mastering of grammar and genre-specific style is emphasized. Additionally students' skills in writing, listening, and speaking of Sanskrit are further developed.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100B. 101B may be taken before 101A with consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4.5 hours of lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong><br/>
6 weeks - 8 hours of lecture per week<br/>
8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> S. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sastraic (Scientific) Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 101C</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sahitya (Literary Sanskrit)</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2017, Spring 2016, Fall 2014<br/>
Introduces students to classical literary Sanskrit (sahitya) and commentary, where available. An extended passage of a kavya and/or an entire plat (naaka) is read, Works of Kalidasa, Bhasa, and the like are normally read. Developing strong reading skills is the focus of the class. Students develop skills to use hard copy and web-based resources. Grammar is reviewed and explained as needed. Students are also introduced to current scholarship and trends in literary analysis. Students are expected to memorize at least one verse per class. Emphasis is placed on correct prosody and pronunciation. Submission of an annotated translation project, assigned in class, is required. Course content changes every semester and may be repeated for credit.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sahitya (Literary Sanskrit):Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="409">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Objectives &amp; Outcomes</strong></p>
<p><strong>Course Objectives:</strong> Intensive language instruction - reading of texts in the original language. Students are expected to prepare readings for translation in class. Mastering of grammar and genre-specific style is emphasized. Additionally students' skills in writing, listening, and speaking of Sanskrit are further developed.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Prerequisite: Sanskrit 100AB or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4.5 hours of lecture per week</p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong><br/>
6 weeks - 8 hours of lecture per week<br/>
8 weeks - 6 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> S. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Sanskrit: Sahitya (Literary Sanskrit):Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 200A</span> <span class="title">Sanskrit Literature</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
Advanced readings in Sanskrit literature, including Sanskrit ornate poetry with emphasis on the canons of poetic analysis of the Indian aesthetic tradition.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Sanskrit Literature:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="157">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101B or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> R.P. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Sanskrit Literature:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 200B</span> <span class="title">Sanskrit Literature</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Advanced readings in Sanskrit literature, including Sanskrit ornate poetry with emphasis on the canons of poetic analysis of the Indian aesthetic tradition.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Sanskrit Literature:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="296">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101B or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> R.P. Goldman</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Sanskrit Literature:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 203</span> <span class="title">Vedic Sanskrit</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2009, Fall 2000, Spring 1999<br/>
Readings from the and other Vedic texts, including and . Knowledge of German and/or French is recommended.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Vedic Sanskrit:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="220">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101B or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Vedic Sanskrit:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 206</span> <span class="title">Middle Indic</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2012, Fall 2011, Spring 2008<br/>
Introduction to Middle Indic. An intensive study of texts in one or more of the Prakrit dialects, Pali, or Apabhramsa.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Middle Indic:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="552">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101B or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Middle Indic:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">SANSKR 207</span> <span class="title">Sanskrit Philosophical Texts</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2012, Spring 2011, Fall 2009<br/>
Reading of a Sanskrit philosophical, logical, or grammatical text, with attention to philosophical, logical, or grammatical features. Text to be chosen in consultation with students.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Sanskrit Philosophical Texts:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="750">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Two years of Sanskrit or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Sanskrit/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Sanskrit Philosophical Texts:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Tamil" name="Tamil"></a>Tamil</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Tamil</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
The grammar of modern Tamil will be covered followed by readings in simple texts. Practice will also be given in spoken Tamil.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="110">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> K. Hart</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Tamil</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
The grammar of modern Tamil will be covered followed by readings in simple texts. Practice will also be given in spoken Tamil.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="22">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> K. Hart</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 101A</span> <span class="title">Readings in Tamil</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
These courses introduce students to a variety of literary styles. 101A will consist of weekly readings and discussions of short stories, poems, and dramatic sketches from representative authors. Short written assignments on themes suggested by the readings are required. Special attention is paid to matters of style and idiom. 101B is devoted to viewing films based on a variety of themes (social, village, mythological, classical Tamil) and to reading scripts and oral written exercises. Students will acquire language skills sufficient to approach literary texts on their own.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="529">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> one-year of Tamil or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> K. Hart</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 101B</span> <span class="title">Readings in Tamil</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
These courses introduce students to a variety of literary styles. 101A will consist of weekly readings and discussions of short stories, poems, and dramatic sketches from representative authors. Short written assignments on themes suggested by the readings are required. Special attention is paid to matters of style and idiom. 101B is devoted to viewing films based on a variety of themes (social, village, mythological, classical Tamil) and to reading scripts and oral written exercises. Students will acquire language skills sufficient to approach literary texts on their own.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Readings in Tamil:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="869">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1-year of Tamil or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> K. Hart</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Readings in Tamil:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 210A</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Tamil Literature</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2016, Fall 2015<br/>
Readings in advanced Tamil. Texts to be determined by the needs of the student.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Tamil Literature:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="260">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Tamil 100B or consent of instructor</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Tamil Literature:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TAMIL 210B</span> <span class="title">Seminar in Tamil Literature</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Readings in advanced Tamil. Texts to be determined by the needs of the student.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Seminar in Tamil Literature:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="651">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100B</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar and 1 hour of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Tamil/Graduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> G. Hart</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Seminar in Tamil Literature:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Telugu" name="Telugu"></a>Telugu</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TELUGU 1A</span> <span class="title">Elementary Telugu</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
The focus of this course will be on systematic grammar, essential vocabulary, and conversations. The goal is to achieve basic reading, writing, and conversational competence as well as exposure to Telugu culture and traditions through language learning. Students will be able to read short stories by the end of this course with some facility.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Elementary Telugu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="98">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A is prerequisite to 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Telugu/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Sunkari</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Elementary Telugu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">TELUGU 1B</span> <span class="title">Elementary Telugu</span> <span class="hours">4 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
The focus of this course will be on systematic grammar, essential vocabulary, and conversations. The goal is to achieve basic reading, writing, and conversational competence as well as exposure to Telugu culture and traditions through language learning. Students will be able to read short stories by the end of this course with some facility.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Elementary Telugu:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="95">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A is a prerequisite for 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 4 hours of lecture and 2 hours of laboratory per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Telugu/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Sunkari</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Elementary Telugu:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Thai" name="Thai"></a>Thai</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 1A</span> <span class="title">Introduction to Thai</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This course is designed for students who have little or no knowledge of the Thai language. The focus of Thai 1A is to build vocabulary and develop the ability to speak with correct pronunciation through basic conversation in day-to-day settings. Students will be introduced to the Thai alphabets and syllable construction rules. To prepare students for intensive literacy acquisition in the spring semester, students are expected to read and write simple words and short sentences by the end of the semester. The class will study common facts about Thailand, etiquette, customs, and values in contemporary Thai culture, through discussion, proverbs, and participation in cultural activities.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introduction to Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="411">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introduction to Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 1B</span> <span class="title">Introduction to Thai</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
Continuing on from the fundamental knowledge of syllable construction learned in Thai 1A, this course is designed to rapidly elevate student's literacy, with the goal of completely abandoning transcription by mid-semester. By the end of the course, students should be reading and writing short descriptive and creative essays, equivalent to 2nd grade students in Thai school. Students continue to learn new vocabulary, grammar and practical thematic conversation with the opportunity to practice with native speakers. Students will also be introduced to Thai customs, culture and value, through a variety of media and cultural activities. Thai is used as the language of instruction up to 20% of the time.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introduction to Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="931">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Thai 1A, (Beginning Introductory Thai) or equivalent, by consent of instructor. Ability to speak some Thai and carry out basic conversation about oneself, family, food, and numbers. Knowledge of the alphabet, and ability to read and write simple words at rudimentary level</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introduction to Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Thai</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This course continues to integrate cultural awareness into language education. The emphasis shifts from the concrete to the abstract. Students will begin to read and write compound sentences, formal essays, and letters. Students will have the opportunity to practice conversation with native speakers. Students will also watch Thai films throughout the semester. Thai as the language of instruction will gradually increase from 20% up to 50%. By the end of the semester, students should have acquired a level of literacy equivalent to 4th grade in Thai schools.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="710">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Thai 1B (Upper Introductory Thai) or equivalent, by consent of instructor. At least medium fluency in spoken and written Thai. Ability to conduct small talk with sufficient fluency. Ability to read and write equivalent to 2nd grade level in Thai school</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Thai</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2016, Spring 2015<br/>
A continuation of Intermediate Thai 100A. Students will learn to read longer and more abstract writing, advertisements from newspapers, and articles from magazines and webpage. The class will cover expressions, figures of speech, higher level grammar, and hierarchical pronouns. Writing will move from descriptive to expository. To increase verbal skills and cultural education, students will watch karaoke, TV advertisements, and films. Students will also have regular intensive conversation practice and in-class presentation. The language of instruction will be in Thai approximately 50% to 70% of the time. By the end of the semester, the average student should have acquired a level of literacy equivalent to 5th to 6th grade in Thai schools.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="69">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Thai 100A (Lower Intermediate Thai) or equivalent, by consent of instructor. Ability to read descriptive articles, and write short composition equivalent to 3rd - 4th grade students in Thai school. Capable of carrying informal conversation on a general subject with medium fluency</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 101A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Thai</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2016, Fall 2015, Fall 2014<br/>
In this third-year course, students further improve active literacy by reading and listening to authentic materials from a variety of contemporary sources including print, web, and broadcast media, and short stories. The class will learn the history of Thailand in the Ayuddhaya period and explore the Thai cultural psyche in order to gain a deeper understanding of cultural values and constructs, their historical development, and the dialectical forces of the old and the new. Students will be required to employ the language in critical analysis and debate in both writing and speech.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="765">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of reading per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">THAI 101B</span> <span class="title">Advanced Thai</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2017, Spring 2016, Spring 2015<br/>
This course is designed to enhance students’ competence in reading and writing Thai. Students will be reading texts from &quot;The Thai Cultural Reader,&quot; newspapers, news from the internet, and selected short stories. The students will improve their listening skills and will discuss selected topics both orally and in writing. The language of instruction is Thai.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Thai:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="408">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of reading per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Thai/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Thai:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h4><a id="Vietnamese" name="Vietnamese"></a>Vietnamese</h4>
<p><span class="legend">Course Descriptions</span></p>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 1A</span> <span class="title">Introductory Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
An introduction to modern spoken and written Vietnamese, including intensive drill on basic phonology and grammar. By the end of the second semester the student should be able to function successfully in ordinary Vietnamese conversation and read simple texts of moderate difficulty.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="886">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A or equivalent or consent of instructor is a prerequiste for 1B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5-5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 1B</span> <span class="title">Introductory Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
An introduction to modern spoken and written Vietnamese, including intensive drill on basic phonology and grammar. By the end of the second semester the student should be able to function successfully in ordinary Vietnamese conversation and read simple texts of moderate difficulty.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Introductory Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="235">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A or equivalent or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Introductory Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 15</span> <span class="title">Intensive Introductory Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">10 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Summer 2016 8 Week Session, Summer 2012 10 Week Session, Summer 2012 8 Week Session<br/>
Provides the learner with essential vocabulary, grammar, and literacy through intensive drills and written and oral exercises. By the end of the course, students should be able to function successfully in everyday Vietnamese conversation and read simple texts of moderate difficulty.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intensive Introductory Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="258">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 20 hours of lecture and 5 hours of discussion per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
<p><strong>Instructor:</strong> Tran</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intensive Introductory Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 100A</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
A second-year course in Vietnamese vocabulary and syntax with intensive drills on short colloquial expressions and auditory recognition of speech patterns. First semester course stresses phraseology, sentence building, rules of composition and development of students' communicative skills. By the end of the second semester students will learn to speak and write simple compositions and will have a cursory introduction to Vietnamese literature and sample readings from contemporary Vietnamese writers.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="65">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 1A-1B, or consent of instructor; 100A or consent of instructor is a prerequisite for 100B</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5-5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Alternative to final exam.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 100B</span> <span class="title">Intermediate Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">5 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
A second-year course in Vietnamese vocabulary and syntax with intensive drills on short colloquial expressions and auditory recognition of speech patterns. First semester course stresses phraseology, sentence building, rules of composition and development of students' communicative skills. By the end of the second semester students will learn to speak and write simple compositions and will have a cursory introduction to Vietnamese literature and sample readings from contemporary Vietnamese writers.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Intermediate Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="305">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100A, or consent of instructor</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 5 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Intermediate Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 101A</span> <span class="title">Advanced Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Fall 2018, Fall 2017, Fall 2016<br/>
This course is designed for students who have already achieved an intermediate degree of proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing modern Vietnamese. Objective: to move students toward a greater level of fluency in each of these key areas and provide an introduction to the literature and culture of Vietnam by reading Vietnamese language texts. Readings will vary from semester to semester and will include novels, short stories, poetry, and essays from the classical, colonial, post-colonial, and contemporary periods. Topics to be addressed in class are the nature of the Sino-Vietnamese classical tradition; cultural legacies of French colonialism; the regional character of literary and cultural production; the emergence of a distinctive Vietnamese modernity, and the history of Vietnamese gender norms and relations. Regular attendance and participation in classroom activities is mandatory and no English will be spoken in class.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="939">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 100B or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="courseblock">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle"><span class="code">VIETNMS 101B</span> <span class="title">Advanced Vietnamese</span> <span class="hours">3 Units</span></h3>
<div class="coursebody">
<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: South and Southeast Asian Studies<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2018, Spring 2017, Spring 2016<br/>
A continuation of 101A, with the goal of conversational fluency, advanced reading competence, and facility in writing. This course also provides an introduction to the literature and culture of Vietnam through a close reading of Vietnamese language texts. Readings will vary from semester to semester and will include novels, short stories, poetry, and essays from the classical, colonial, and contemporary periods. Among the topics to be addressed in class are the nature of the Sino-Vietnamese classical tradition, the cultural legacies of French colonialism, the regional character of literary and cultural production, the emergence of a distinctive Vietnamese modernity, and the history of Vietnamese gender norms and relations. Regular attendance and participation in classroom activities is mandatory and no English will be spoken in class.</span><br/>
<a class="btn-readmore" href="">Advanced Vietnamese:Read More [+]</a></p>
<div aria-expanded="false" class="coursedetails" id="922">
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p>
<p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> 101A or equivalent</p>
<p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with instructor consent.</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p>
</div>
<div class="course-section">
<p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p>
<p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Vietnamese/Undergraduate</p>
<p><strong>Grading/Final exam status:</strong> Letter grade. Final exam required.</p>
</div>
<p><a class="btn-readless" href="">Advanced Vietnamese:Read Less [-]</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>+ </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Janaki Bakhle, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lawrence Cohen, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Social cultural anthropology, medical and psychiatric anthropology, critical gerontology, lesbian and gay studies, feminist and queer theory.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14619"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Jacob Dalton, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Religion, ritual, Tibet, Buddhism, Tantra, Dunhuang.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14626"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Penelope S. C. Edwards, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Munis D. Faruqui, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Mughal India, Delhi Sultanate, Islam in South Asia/India, Urdu.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14655"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Robert P. Goldman, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Literary theory, South and Southeast Asian studies, Sanskrit literature, Indian epic studies, and psychoanalytically oriented cultural studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14726"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Vasudha Paramasivan, <i>Assistant Professor</i>. </strong>Hindi Literature, Hinduism, South Asian Literature and Culture.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16426"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Raka Ray, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Feminist theory, gender, social movements, South and Southeast Asian studies, relations between dominant subaltern groups in India, womenÂ´_s movements in India.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15263"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Sylvia C. Tiwon, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Indonesia, South and Southeast Asian studies, literature and gender, cultural studies of Southeast Asia, discourse oral, print, electronic, socio-cultural formations at the national and sub-nation level, non-governmental organizations.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15546"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Alexander Von Rospatt, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Ritual studies, Nepalese studies, Buddhist traditions of South Asia, doctrinal history, Newar Buddhism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15585"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Peter B. Zinoman, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Vietnam, Vietnam War, Vietnamese literature, Southeast Asian history, communism, nationalism, colonialism.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15658"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturer</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Amitabha Basu, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gregory Bruce, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Cynthia Agnes C. Aban, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Maria Barrios-Leblanc, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Supatra Chowchuvech, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Sally J. Goldman, <i>Senior Lecturer</i>. </strong>Women's studies, South and Southeast Asian studies, buddhist Sanskrit, Pali, Prakrit, Sanskrit language, valmiki ramayana translation project, South Asian women, epic and classical Sanskrit literature, vyakarana or Sanskrit grammar, Veda.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14727"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karen Llagas, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ninik Lunde, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Linguistics, comparative literature, South and Southeast Asian studies, Indonesian language, Javanese, Balinese and Sumatranese dances.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15077"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Cam Nguyen, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bharathy Sankara Rajulu, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Pranjali Sirasao, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Francis J. Smith, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hanh Tran, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Upkar K. Ubhi, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong>Architecture, South and Southeast Asian studies, Punjabi, curriculum developments, marketing trends, building arts.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15562"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Kenneth Wong, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Vasudha Dalmia, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>George L. Hart, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>South and Southeast Asian studies, Tamil studies, classical Sanskrit, South Indian religion and culture, Indian civilization, Indian literature, Indian religion.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14800"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Usha R. Jain, <i>Senior Lecturer Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Padmanabh S. Jaini, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ James A. Matisoff, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Linguistics, Japanese, Southeast Asian languages, Tibeto-Burman, Thai, Chinese, field linguistics, Yiddish studies, historical semantics, psychosemantics, language typology, areal linguistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15094"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Bruce R. Pray, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joanna Williams, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

