<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Designated Emphasis (DE) in Dutch Studies provides curricular and research resources for students who want to concentrate on Dutch Studies within their respective disciplines and have their work formally recognized in their degree designation. Designed to bring together faculty and students from different departments, the DE will be administered by the Graduate Group in Dutch Studies and will provide a unique context for rigorous cross-disciplinary research. Sponsoring departments include German, History, History of Art, Southeast Asian Studies, African-American Studies, Comparative Literature, French, and Sociology. However, the DE is open to interested students regardless of whether their home department is officially affiliated with the DE. The program will help advance Berkeley’s position as America’s leading Dutch studies program and facilitate research in and cooperation with other universities in the Netherlands, Belgium, South Africa, Indonesia, and the Caribbean, for example, who also have strong Dutch studies programs. Students applying to the DE must be prepared to integrate high-level research in Dutch studies into their coursework, qualifying exam and dissertation.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>To be admitted to the Designated Emphasis in Development Engineering, an applicant must already be accepted into a PhD program at the University of California, Berkeley. For further information regarding admission to graduate programs at UC Berkeley, please see the <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">Graduate Division's Admissions website</a>.</p>
<p>Students are required to fill out a form requesting admission, listing their prior preparation in the field, and their projected pathway through the program. In addition, they have to submit a brief essay stating interests and reasons for applying, a CV, a writing sample, and a letter of recommendation from a faculty member in the student’s home department indicating why and how the student would benefit from the DE.</p>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Students must be admitted to the DE prior to taking their qualifying exams. Admission will be determined on the basis of how coherently and logically the student can articulate the value of the DE for her/his larger course of study and career goals, as well as on the quality of the written work.</p>
]]>
</admissionstext>
<designatedemphasisrequriementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Curriculum/Coursework</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Students admitted to the designated emphasis program must complete the following requirements before applying for their qualifying examination:</p>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%">
<caption class="hidden noscript">Course List</caption>
<colgroup><col class="codecol"/><col class="titlecol"/><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol"/></colgroup><thead><tr class="hidden noscript"><th scope="col">Code</th><th scope="col">Title</th><th scope="col" class="hourscol">Units</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr class="even areaheader  firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Language Requirement</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">DUTCH 100</td><td>Dutch for Reading Knowledge <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass odd"><td class="codecol orclass">or DUTCH 1</td><td colspan="2"> Elementary Dutch</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Integrative Course</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">DUTCH 299</td><td>Individual Studies in Dutch for Graduate Students <sup>2</sup></td><td class="hourscol">1-8</td></tr>
<tr class="even areaheader "><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader ">Electives</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Select two additional courses related to Dutch Studies, from the following approved list; at least one must be a graduate seminar:</span> <sup>3</sup></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">AFRICAM 118</div></td><td>The Slave Trade and Culture in the Modern Atlantic World [3]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">AFRICAM 131</div></td><td>Caribbean Societies and Cultures [3]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 107</div></td><td>The Structure of Modern Dutch [3]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 110</div></td><td>Advanced Dutch [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 125</div></td><td>Conversation and Composition [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 140</div></td><td>Topics in Dutch Literature [3]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH C164</div></td><td>The Indonesian Connection: Dutch Literature About the Indies in English Translation [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 166</div></td><td>Anne Frank and After: World War II and the Holocaust in the Netherlands [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 170</div></td><td>Multiculturalism in the Netherlands [3]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH C170</div></td><td>Dutch Culture and Society: Amsterdam and Berkeley in the Sixties [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 171AC</div></td><td>From New Amsterdam to New York: Race, Culture, and Identity in New Netherland [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 174</div></td><td>Brussels: A Global Study of a European Capital City [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 173</div></td><td>Dutch Post-Colonial Studies [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH C178</div></td><td>Cultural Studies [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 179</div></td><td>Cultural Studies [3,4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">DUTCH 299</div></td><td>Individual Studies in Dutch for Graduate Students [1-8] <sup>4</sup></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">GERMAN 280</div></td><td>North Sea Germanic [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 108</div></td><td>Cities and the Arts [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 166</div></td><td>Van Eyck to Brueghel [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 172</div></td><td>The Dutch Golden Age [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 173</div></td><td>The Age of Rubens [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 260</div></td><td>Seminar in Italian Renaissance Art [2,4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTART 262</div></td><td>Seminar in European Art [2,4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTORY 112B</div></td><td>Africa: Modern South Africa, 1652-Present [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even lastrow"><td class="codecol"><div style="margin-left:20px;" class="blockindent">HISTORY 170</div></td><td>The Netherlands [4]</td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<table border="0" width="100%" class="sc_footnotes"><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>1</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>Students who already possess a basic knowledge of Dutch can apply for dispensation of this requirement. In order to do so, their knowledge of Dutch has to be examined and officially acknowledged in a letter written by a member of the Dutch Studies Program in the Department of German.</p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>2</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>This course will serve as the integrative course for the program regarding methodology and research skills. The student needs to write a 7000-word article to complete the course, using a bibliography that includes Dutch studies materials. The ultimate goal is to elaborate an article in close cooperation with the supervising faculty member(s) that can be published in an academic journal in the field of Dutch studies (such as <em>Dutch Crossing</em>, <em>Journal of Dutch Literature</em>, or <em>The Low Countries</em>), or any other academic journal.</p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>3</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>Students may petition for a course not on this established list if approved by the advising committee.</p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>4</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>One of the two-course electives can be fulfilled by repeating <span class="sc_courseinline">DUTCH 299</span>, under the condition that the topic of this course changes.</p></td></tr></table>
<h3>Qualifying Examination</h3>
<p class="Normal1">A member of the Graduate Group in Dutch Studies must be a formal member of the PhD qualifying examination committee of the DE student. Under most circumstances, the Graduate Group member in the student’s home department will serve in this function. A member of the graduate group may also serve as the outside member of the qualifying exam committee if not a faculty member of the student’s major. At least one Dutch studies topic must be included as a subject on the qualifying examination. Satisfactory performance on the qualifying examination for the PhD will be judged according to the established rules in the student’s major program.</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Dissertation</h3>
<p class="Normal1">A member of the Graduate Group in Dutch Studies must be a formal member of the dissertation committee of the DE student. The dissertation must (partially) relate to Dutch studies (such as Dutch culture, history, politics, art, literature, linguistics, or sociology).</p>
<h3 class="Normal1">Degree conferral</h3>
<p class="Normal1">Upon completion of all requirements of the student’s major program and the DE in Dutch Studies, students will receive a designation on their transcript and diploma stating that they have completed a “PhD in ( . . . ) with a Designated Emphasis in Dutch Studies.”</p>
]]>
</designatedemphasisrequriementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Dutch Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="coursedescs_toggleAll notinpdf"><button class="btn_expandAll">Expand all course descriptions [+]</button><button class="btn_collapseAll">Collapse all course descriptions [-]</button></div>
<div class="courseblock">
<button class="btn_toggleCoursebody" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="cb_dutch299" data-toggle="#cb_dutch299">
<h3 class="courseblocktitle">
<span class="code">DUTCH 299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Studies in Dutch for Graduate Students</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 8 Units</span>
</h3>
</button>
<div class="coursebody" aria-hidden="true" id="cb_dutch299">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Offered through: German<br/>
Terms offered: Spring 2020, Fall 2019, Spring 2019<br/>
For graduate students engaged in exploration of a restricted field, involving the writing of a research paper.</span><br/>
 <a href="" class="btn-readmore"><span>Individual Studies in Dutch for Graduate Students:</span> Read More [+]</a></p>
<div id="229" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit without restriction.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-8 hours of independent study per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 1.5-15 hours of independent study per week</p><!--<p class=""><strong>Additional Format:</strong> Individual conference.</p>--></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Dutch/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
<p><a href="" class="btn-readless"><span>Individual Studies in Dutch for Graduate Students:</span> Read Less [-] </a></p></div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><p class="facitem"><strong>+ </strong>Indicates this faculty member is the recipient of the Distinguished Teaching Award.</p><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Jeroen Dewulf, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Dutch studies, transatlantic slavery, German literature, European Studies, post-colonial studies, hybridity.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14542"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Karen Feldman, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, aesthetics, literary theory, Kant, Nietzsche, Heidegger, Arendt, Benjamin, 18th-20th century German thought, Hegel, Adorno.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14663"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Deniz Gokturk, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>German literature, German cinema, transnational cinemas, German-Turkish-European-American intersections in cinema, performance and spectatorship and reception, intertextuality and intermediality and translation, the politics and poetics of migration and globalization, urban imaginaries and mediations of place, theories of diversity and nationalism, comedy and community, modern rituals of regulating identity and authority and mobility.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14723"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Anton Kaes, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Film studies, modern literature, literary and cultural theory, cinema, interdisciplinary and comparative aspects of Weimar culture, contemporary literature and film, literary theory, theory of cultural studies, film history, film theory, history of cinema.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14903"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Winfried Kudszus, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Psychoanalysis, semiotics, culture, literature, philosophy, psychology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14939"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Niklaus Largier, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Religion, literature, German, history of medieval and early modern German literature, theology, mysticism, secularism, senses, sensuality, history of emotions, passions, asceticism, flagellation, sexuality.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14949"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Irmengard Rauch, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Semiotics, Germanic linguistics, linguistic archeology, paralanguage, Old Saxon, Old Frisian, linguistic fieldwork, socio-cultural and cognitive approaches to language variation and language change, contrastive analysis and linguistic methodology, Gothic, Modern High German and its dialects, Old/Middle High/Early New High German.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15609"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Thomas F. Shannon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Linguistics, control, German, Dutch, syntax, phonology, naturalness, syllable structure, complementation, ergative phenomena, passivization, perfect auxiliary selection, word order, processing factors syntactic phenomena, cognitive, functional grammar, corpus.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15668"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Chenxi Tang, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>European intellectual history, German literature from the eighteenth to the early twentieth century, political and legal thought, cultural theory, early modern European literature, Europe and China.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15686"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Elaine C. Tennant, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>German, Habsburg court society in the early modern period, the development of the German language at the end of the middle ages, the Middle High German narrative tradition, literary and cultural traditions of the holy roman empire, European reactions.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15668"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Affiliated Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Judith Butler, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Critical theory, gender and sexuality studies, comparative literature, 19th and 20th century continental philosophy, social and political thought, philosophy and literature.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/judith-butler"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Pheng Cheah, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Nationalism, rhetoric, legal philosophy, feminism, 18th-20th century continental philosophy and contemporary critical theory, postcolonial theory and anglophone postcolonial literatures, cosmopolitanism and globalization, social and political thought.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14527"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Connelly, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John M. Efron, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Cultural and social history of German Jewry.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16360"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Beate Fricke, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Medieval art and architecture, idolatry, iconoclasm, history of allegory, formation of communities, incest, anthropophagy, animation, emergence of life and procreation, theories and practices in use of images and relics, visual and material culture, Carolingian Art, Gothic Art, Ottonian Art.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14691"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hannah Ginsborg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Philosophy, Kant and on Kantian themes in contemporary epistemology and philosophy of mind.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14714"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Mel Gordon, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Stefan-Ludwig Hoffmann, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Modern German and European History, Conceptual History, Transnational History, urban studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/16948"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>John Lindow, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Old Norse-Icelandic literature, Scandinavian folklore, Finno-Ugric folklore, Pre-Christian religion of the North, Scandinavian mythology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14231"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Linda H. Rugg, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Scandinavian, Swedish literature and culture 1870 to the present, August Strindberg, Ingmar Bergman, visual autobiography, literature and the visual arts, ecology and culture, film, whiteness studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15414"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hans Sluga, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Political philosophy, recent European philosophy, history of analytic philosophy, Frege, Wittgenstein, Foucault.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15462"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gary B. Holland, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Historical linguistics, Indo-European linguistics, poetics, early Indo-European languages, linguistic typology, historical syntax, history of linguistics.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14854"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><h4>Lecturers</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Yael Chaver, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Nikolaus Euba, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Harriett Virginia Ann Jernigan, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Esmee Van Der Hoeven, <i>Lecturer</i>. </strong></p><h4>Visiting Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Charlton Payne, <i>Visiting Researcher</i>. </strong></p><h4>Emeritus Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>Bluma Goldstein, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Gerd Hillen, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>+ Claire Kramsch, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Language, culture, pragmatics, society, education, applied linguistics, aesthetics, literacy, second language acquisition, language pedagogy, language in discourse, hermeneutic approaches to language learning.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14934"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Joseph Mileck, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Klaus Mueller, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Hinrich C. Seeba, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>18th 20th century German literature and culture, intellectual and institutional, enlightenment, Napoleonic era, vormarz, concepts and images history, role language nationalism, contemporary trends German literature, representations urban space.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15662"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Johan P. Snapper, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong>Dutch studies.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15469"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Frederic C. Tubach, <i>Professor Emeritus</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

