<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<introductiontostudentlifetext>
<![CDATA[
<p>With more than 40,000 students, a distinguished faculty, 184 degree programs, and alumni in positions of national and international leadership, UC Berkeley offers students a wide arena for academic and personal growth. <span id="docs-internal-guid-b0bf4181-128d-2e0f-f48a-2d6d40224cba">Campus staff and faculty are dedicated to supporting students holistically throughout their learning journey. Students will find myriad programs and services that enhance understanding of their own values and that introduce them to new and different perspectives. </span></p>
<p>Please visit the following UC Berkeley websites to learn more about Berkeley and student life. In addition, explore the tabbed information on this page to learn more.</p>
<p><strong>Be Berkeley</strong><br/>
The <a href="https://admissions.berkeley.edu/be-berkeley" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Admissions website</a> offers a good overview to everything the campus has to offer, including Sports &amp; Athletics, Housing, Diversity, Faculty, Clubs &amp; Organizations, Arts &amp; Culture, Jobs &amp; Careers, Life in the Bay, and Health &amp; Safety. </p>
<p><strong>Cal Student Central</strong><br/>
<a href="https://studentcentral.berkeley.edu/">Cal Student Central</a> is your destination for key university business related to financial aid, fees and billing, payments, disbursements, registration, and enrollment.</p>
<p><strong>New Student Services (NSS)</strong><br/>
The <a href="https://orientation.berkeley.edu/">New Student Services'</a> mission is to give each student the support and resources needed for a successful transition to the Berkeley campus.</p>
]]>
</introductiontostudentlifetext>
<disabledstudentsprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Disabled Students’ Program (DSP) is located at 260 Cesar Chavez Student Center. If you have a documented and verifiable disability, you may be eligible for academic accommodations and auxiliary services (such as lab assistance, notetakers, and Sign Language interpreters). If you have a visual, hearing, mobility, physical disability, or a learning or other nonapparent disability, contact DSP (Voice: 510-642-0518; TTY: 510-642-6376) or visit the <a href="http://dsp.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Disabled Students’ Program website.</a></p>
]]>
</disabledstudentsprogramtext>
<theucberkeleystorytext>
<![CDATA[
<p>Founded in the wake of the gold rush by leaders of the newly established 31st state, the University of California's flagship campus at Berkeley is now one of the top-ranked universities in the world. Originally charged with providing education (both &quot;practical&quot; and &quot;classical&quot;) to the state's people, Berkeley gradually established a distinguished faculty (with 38 Nobel laureates to date), 14 colleges and schools, and more than 280 degree programs.</p>
<p>This California institution became a catalyst of economic growth and social innovation — the place where vitamin E was discovered, a lost Scarlatti opera found, the flu virus identified, and the nation's first no-fault divorce law drafted. Scholars at Berkeley have conducted groundbreaking research on topics ranging from urban street gangs to basic human nutritional requirements. They have identified why wartime supply ships were failing at sea, invented technologies to build faster and cheaper computer chips, and imaged the infant universe.</p>
<p>In accordance with UC's &quot;public&quot; character, the university has long served talented individuals regardless of means. As early as 1897, financial aid was available for &quot;needy and deserving&quot; students. More than a century later, UC Berkeley combines outstanding teaching and research programs with broad access for students of all means — educating more federal Pell Grant recipients from low-income families than all eight Ivy League universities combined. Seventeen percent of UC Berkeley freshmen are the first in their families to attend college.</p>
<p>For more information, v<a href="http://www.berkeley.edu/about/" target="_blank">isit the UC Berkeley gateway site</a> and check out <a href="https://www.berkeley.edu/about/bythenumbers">Berkeley: By the Numbers</a>.</p>
]]>
</theucberkeleystorytext>
<universityofcaliforniatext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The University of California is composed of 10 campuses, each with a distinctive character: San Francisco (established in 1873), Davis (1909), Los Angeles (1919), Riverside (1954), Santa Barbara (1958), San Diego (1960), Irvine (1965) Santa Cruz (1965), and Merced (2005). The University has five law schools, five medical schools, and schools of architecture, business administration, education, engineering, and many others.  Some 480 laboratories, extension centers, and research and field stations strengthen teaching and research while providing public service to California and the country.</p>
<p>Over 230,000 students attend the University of California and about 75 percent of them are California residents. For more information about the University of California, please<a href="http://www.universityofcalifornia.edu" target="_blank"> visit the University of California website</a>. </p>
]]>
</universityofcaliforniatext>
<consumerinformationanddisclosurestext>
<![CDATA[
<p>Federal regulations require all institutions to provide specified information to prospective and current students, staff, and the general public. Listed below are those items that must be available for review per federal regulations.</p>
<p>The federal Higher Education Act, the federal Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act (EADA), and regulatory guidance provided in the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) require direct individual notices of prescribed information to certain target audiences including prospective students, currently enrolled students, current employees, parents, coaches and counselors of prospective student-athletes, and the general public. Disclosures are to include crime/security statistics, student completion/graduation rates, FERPA privacy/security rights, financial aid program information, and gender-specific information on athletic participation and financial support.</p>
<p><strong>Accreditation</strong> – UC Berkeley is accredited by the Western Association of Schools and Colleges (WASC). For complete information on institutional and program accreditation, visit the <a href="http://vcue.berkeley.edu/committees-initiatives/campus-accreditation/2015-accreditation-review-documents" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Accreditation website.</a></p>
<p><strong>Athletics</strong> – Information on the participation rates and financing of UC Berkeley’s intercollegiate athletic programs may be found at the <a href="http://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ope/index.html" target="_blank">U.S. Office of Postsecondary Education website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Campus Buildings and Facilities</strong> – For a virtual visit or other types of campus tours, see the <a href="http://www.berkeley.edu/about/visit" target="_blank">UC Berkeley Visit page.</a></p>
<p><strong>Campus Security Report</strong> – The campus security report for current and previous years, including information required by the Jeanne Clery Act, is viewable on the <a href="http://ucpd.berkeley.edu/our-divisions/administration/community-outreach/clery-act/uc-berkeley-campus-annual-security-report" target="_blank">UC Police Department's website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Cost of Attendance</strong> – Information on the cost of attendance at UC Berkeley can be found on the Registration Fees page of the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/current_students/registration_enrollment/feesched.html" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar's website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Degree Programs</strong> – For a complete list of programs at UC Berkeley, use this Guide or go to the <a href="http://www.berkeley.edu/academics/dept/a.shtml" target="_blank">Academic Departments and Programs website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Faculty</strong> – Current faculty lists are grouped by academic department and program and can be found on the UC Berkeley<a href="http://www.berkeley.edu/academics/dept/a.shtml" target="_blank"> website</a> or in the Guide on the degree and department pages.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Aid</strong> – To find out more about the financial aid available to students, go to the <a href="http://financialaid.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Financial Aid and Scholarships Office's website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Graduation/Completion Rates</strong> – Campus graduation rates can be found in the Undergraduate Profile and Graduate Profile documents available on the <a href="http://opa.berkeley.edu/statistics/index.html" target="_blank">Office of Planning &amp; Analysis website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Higher Education Act Disclosures</strong> – Required disclosures of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by the Higher Education Opportunity Act of 2008 are available on the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/headisclosures.html" target="_blank">Office of the Registrar's website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Refund Policy for Financial Aid Students</strong> – For information about requirements for the return of financial aid funds when a student withdraws from school, go to the Withdrawing from Classes or School page on the <a href="http://students.berkeley.edu/finaid/undergraduates/withdrawal.htm" target="_blank">Financial Aid and Scholarships Office website</a><a href="http://financialaid.berkeley.edu/withdrawing-classes-or-school">.</a></p>
<p><strong>Satisfactory Academic Progress</strong> – Requirements for satisfactory academic progress for students on financial aid is found on the Satisfactory Academic Progress page on the <a href="https://financialaid.berkeley.edu/satisfactory-academic-progress" target="_blank">Financial Aid and Scholarships Office website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Student Concerns and Complaints</strong> – Students who encounter challenging behaviors or difficult interactions on campus regarding academic, student services or conduct issues can find information and assistance via the <a href="http://campuslife.berkeley.edu/ombuds" target="_blank">Ombuds Office web page</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Services for Disabled Students</strong> – For full information on services available to disabled students, visit the <a href="http://dsp.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">Disabled Students' Program website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Student Privacy Rights</strong> – To learn about how UC Berkeley protects your right to the privacy of your confidential educational records, view the <a href="http://registrar.berkeley.edu/academic-policies-procedures/ferpa" target="_blank">Disclosure of Information from Student Records document</a> (PDF).</p>
]]>
</consumerinformationanddisclosurestext>
<organizationandadministrationtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>Under the State Constitution, the government of the University is entrusted to the Board of Regents. The regents appoint the president of the University, and with the president’s advice, appoint the chancellors, directors of major laboratories, provosts, and deans who administer the affairs of the individual campuses and other divisions of the University. Authority in academic matters is delegated by the regents to the Academic Senate, which determines academic policy for the University as a whole.</p>
<p>The Board of Regents includes seven ex-officio board members and 14 members who are appointed by the governor for 12-year terms after consultation with an advisory committee. In addition, the regents appoint a student regent for a one-year term as a voting board member with full rights of participation. The chair and vice chair of the Academic Council serve as faculty representatives to the board and participate fully in all discussions. A constitutional amendment provides that “Regents shall be able persons broadly reflective of the economic, cultural, and social diversity of the State, including ethnic minorities and women.” They shall have “full powers of organization and government, subject only to such legislative controls as may be necessary to ensure compliance with the terms of the endowments of the University and the security of its funds.”</p>
<p>The president is executive head of the ten-campus University system. The Office of the President, located in Oakland, is the University’s central administrative headquarters. There are eight divisions: Academic Affairs, Agriculture and Natural Resources, Business Operations, External Relations, Finance, General Counsel, Health Sciences and Services, and Laboratory Management. The Office of the President performs administrative functions for the University as a whole and supports all campus operations.</p>
<p>Each of the campuses has a chancellor as its chief administrative officer. The chancellor is responsible for the organization and operation of the campus, including academic, student, and business affairs. For the names of University regents, officers, and chancellors, see the <a href="/2018-19/student-life/#officersofadministrationtext">Officers of Administration tab. </a></p>
<p>The <a href="https://academic-senate.berkeley.edu/">Academic Senate</a> is empowered by the Regents to determine academic policy, set conditions for admission and granting of degrees, advise the Chancellor on the campus budget, authorize and supervise courses and curricula, and advise the administration on faculty appointments, promotions, and budgets. </p>
<p>Students participate in policymaking at both the campus and Universitywide levels.</p>
<p>For more information, please <a href="http://regents.universityofcalifornia.edu" target="_blank">visit the Board of Regents website</a>. </p>
]]>
</organizationandadministrationtext>
<officersofadministrationtext>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://regents.universityofcalifornia.edu/about/members-and-advisors/index.html" target="_blank">Members of the Board of Regents and Advisers to the Board</a><br/>
<a href="http://regents.universityofcalifornia.edu/about/officers.html" target="_blank">Officers of the Regents</a><br/>
<a href="http://www.ucop.edu/  " target="_blank">UC Office of the President</a><br/>
<a href=" http://www.ucop.edu/business-operations/_files/opchart.pdf" target="_blank">UC Office of the President Org Chart</a> <br/>
<a href="http://www.berkeley.edu/admin/org.shtml" target="_blank">Key Administrators, Berkeley</a></p>
]]>
</officersofadministrationtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

